

Tameem Siddiqui

SAFETY MANAGER

My Contact



Address

Makkah, Saudi Arabia

Phone

+966592918558

⊠ Email

s.tameem@alayuni.com tameem_siddiqui@yahoo.com

Education

- Masters in Safety & Environment Management KEN Institute of Executive Learning
- B. Tech, Civil Engineering Manav Bharti University
- Lead Auditor, ISO 45001:2018. QUALITY AUSTRIA CENTRAL ASIA PVT.LTD
- NEBOSH Shieldz Technologies
- Fire & Safety Engineering, OSHA NIFE College
- Intermediate with Maths, Physics & Chemistry Dharmavanth Junior College
- S. S. C Jawahar High School

About Me

I am a Safety Manager at Al-Ayuni, with previous 15 years of experience in Health & Safety field working in the professional environment where I contribute my expertise skills and responsibly complete my due duties with complete honesty and enthusiasm.

Work Experience

Al-Ayuni | Safety Manager

September, 2021 - Present

Safety Manager at Al-Ayuni Company, Al-Eskan road near 4th ring road project & Faculty of Education at Makkah, Umal Qura University Project, Saudi Arabia.

Al-Ayuni | Safety Manager

September, 2020 - September, 2021

Safety Manager at Al-Ayuni company, NEOM Sharma to Tabuk Road Tabuk, Saudi Arabia.

Al-Ayuni | Safety Manager

July, 2019 - September, 2020

Safety Manager at Al-Ayuni Company, Al-Qadimah Naval Port Project, Thuwal, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.

Beijing Construction Engineering | Safety Manager

August, 2013- June, 2019

Safety Manager at Beijing Construction Engineering Group (BCEG), R.C Headquarter Project Yanbu, Saudi Arabia.

Saudi E-Pay Company | Safety Supervisor

May, 2012 -July 2013

Safety Supervisor at Saudi E-Pay Company, King Abdullah Sports City Stadium Project, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.

ABV Rock Group Ltd | Safety Engineer

June, 2010 - April 2012

Safety Engineer at ABV Rock Group Ltd, King Saud University Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.

Experience in India (2 Years):

Glass Architectural Solutions | FIRE & SAFETY-SUPERVISOR 2008-2010

Worked as FIRE &SAFETY-SUPERVISOR in Glass Architectural Solutions. Hyderabad, India

Personal Profile

- Nationality: Indian
- Religion: Islam
- Marital status: Married
- Sex: Male
- Languages: English, Hindi, Urdu and Arabic

Career Summary

I am a dedicated Occupational Health & Safety Professional with 15 years of construction field experience. Expert at inspecting and evaluating workplace for safety hazards and recommending and implementing safe workplace policies and procedures. Licensed and certified to administer and training skills with proven ability to interact effectively with technicians and management at all

Personal Traits

I am considered a leader in our team when it comes to special and regular projects whose core responsibility to execute work with in time maintaining safety by using all safety measures. Adaptive to varied environment and open to learn new tools and technologies. I am habituated of working with a team, very much comfortable working with my team size. Quite confident of achieving my set goals and targets. Good interpersonal and communication skills.

Duties & Responsibilities

- Ensure that every individual must adopt and follow the laws of safety in their respective job on site.
- Regularly monitoring and analysis of hazards and recommends for preventive measure to avoid and minimize occurrence accidents in future.
- Ensure all activities are carried out within well structured environment with a clear reporting framework.
- Regular meeting with the managers on operating matters and work priorities.
- Orientation to implement emergency and rescue procedures, first aid facility ambulance must be available all the time to meet an emergency.
- Responsible for identifying safety deficiencies of the workers and to instruct and suggest them to take all possible measure to execute the work with safety.
- Daily monitoring for the workers at the job site area to ensure the supervisor/foreman conduct the safety toolbox.
- Meeting before they start work.
- Evaluates and rates individual HSE performance of the workers. Administrating work permit on certain other safe work procedure and recommending solutions.
- Advising on proper selection and use of personal protective equipment and efficient working condition.
- To create safety awareness by promoting safety meeting presentations and open forum discussions.
- Assists in development and implementation of health and safety procedures.
- Review and inspection of critical and heavy lifts.
- Review and implementation of scaffold safety requirement using both system scaffolds and tube coupler scaffolds.
- Coordination of sub-contractor's activities to reduce and correct hazards.
- Incident investigation, report presentation and follow up corrective actions.
- Reports all unsafe conditions and practices and take corrective actions. Experienced in dealing with various types of people in different situation.